Daehwa Kim

407 South Craig Street, Pittsburgh, PA 15213 daehwak@andrew.cmu.edu • +1 415 937 4111 • https://daehwa.github.io

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research goal is to invent technologies that could change the interaction paradigm as if the invention of "mouse" paved the way for the world of GUIs. I believe that preferable devices by users could decide next decades of interaction paradigm. To do so, I care about the tangled relationship between what humans are already familiar with, feel comfortable with, and emotionally attracted to, and what kind of technological / design problems to solve. Some demonstrations of this idea are published - explored novel sensing principles of segmenting effortless finger touch (AtaTouch) and shifting the form factor of the micro-gesture sensing device to a wristband from a ring (EtherPose). I presented papers at ACM CHI and UIST and have received two Honorable Mention awards at CHI.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. student, Carnegie Mellon University, School of Computer Science,

Sep 2022 – Current

Human-Computer Interaction Institute

Advised by Prof. Chris Harrison at Future Interfaces Group

M.Sc., KAIST, School of Computing

Mar 2019 - Feb 2021

- Advised by Prof. Geehyuk Lee at Human-Computer Interaction Lab
- Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" (2020 Best Thesis Award)

B.S., UNIST, Electrical and Computer Engineering

Mar 2015 – Feb 2019

- Computer Science and Engineering (Major) and Electrical Engineering (Minor)
- Entered with top honors.
- Summer session program, University of the Arts London, London, UK

Jul 2018

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Meta Reality Labs, Redmond, WA

- Research Intern
- Mentor: Dr. Eric Whitmire

Future Interfaces Group, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA

Sep 2021 – Apr 2022

May 2023 – Aug 2023

- Research Associate, Human-Computer Interaction Institute
- Advisor: Prof. Chris Harrison

KAIST HCI Lab, Daejeon

Mar 2018 – Jun 2018

- Undergraduate Research Student, School of Computing
- Advisor: Prof. Geehyuk Lee

Hyper-connected Communication Research Laboratory, ETRI

Jan 2018 – Mar 2018

Research Intern

AWARDS & HONORS

Best Paper Honorable Mention Award, ACM CHI 2022

May 2022

 Craig Shultz, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Karan Ahuja, and Chris Harrison, "TriboTouch: Micro-Patterned Surfaces for Low Latency Touchscreens" in *Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, New Orleans, LA, USA, Apr 2022.

Best Paper Honorable Mention Award, ACM CHI 2021

May 2021

<u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return Loss" in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan.

Best Master's Thesis Award, KAIST School of Computing

Feb 2021

■ Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras"

Uni-Star Scholarship, UNIST

Mar 2015 - Feb 2019

Tuition + academic funding every semester for the top rank in entrance exam

PUBLICATIONS

- [1] Hui-Shyong Yeo, Erwin Wu, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Juyoung Lee, Hyung-il Kim, Seo Young Oh, Luna Takagi, Woontack Woo, Hideki Koike, and Aaron J Quigley, "OmniSense: Exploring Novel Input Sensing and Interaction Techniques on Mobile Device with Omni-Directional Camera" in *Proceedings of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Hamburg, Germany, Apr 2023.
- [2] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, and Chris Harrison, "EtherPose: Continuous Hand Pose Tracking with Wrist-Worn Antenna Impedance" in *Proceedings of the 35th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology*, Bend, Oregon, USA, Oct 2022.
- [3] Craig Shultz, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Karan Ahuja, and Chris Harrison, "TriboTouch: Micro-Patterned Surfaces for Low Latency Touchscreens" in *Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, New Orleans, LA, USA, Apr 2022. Best Paper Honorable Mention Award; Top 5%
- [4] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return Loss" in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan. <u>Best Paper Honorable Mention Award</u>; Top 5%
- [5] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "OddEyeCam: A Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" in *Proceedings of* the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology, Virtual Event, USA, Oct 2020.
- [6] Keunwoo Park, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Seongkook Heo, and Geehyuk Lee, "MagTouch: Robust Finger Identification for a Smartwatch Using a Magnet Ring and a Built-in Magnetometer" in *Proceedings* of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, Honolulu, Hawaii, USA, Apr 2020.

ACADEMIC SERVICE

Reviewer

SIGGRAPH '23 Poster, UIST '23, CHI '23, UIST '22, CHI '22 LBW, IMWUT '21, CHI '21 LBW